American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIg. 1887-1891 APS.Archives.IIg APS.Archives.IIg
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Feb. 21, 1889; 3x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Thanks him for eyeglasses case. Refers to Robert Aitken, G.P. Philes, G. de Melatesta.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Feb. 23, 1889; 8x4-3/4; Ridler, C. E.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks about "Poor Richard's almanacks" in A.P.S. collection On verso is draft of Phillips' reply. See H. Phillips to C.E. Ridler, [Feb. 25, 1889].
  - Letter to [C. E. Ridler;], Feb. 25, 1889; 8x3-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Draft. Enc. wanting. Sends list of "Poor Richard's almanacks" in A.P.S. collection. Written on verso of letter, C.E. Ridler to [H. Phillips], Feb. 23, 1889.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Feb. 27, 1889; 9x5-1/2; Jayne, Horace, 1859-1913
    [Phila.], Typed L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Encloses sketch of Andrew Blair.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., Feb. 28, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend next meeting. Refers to U.S. Coast Survey.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Feb. 28, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns a possible paper on folk medicine.
  - Letter to H.M. Phillips [Henry Phillips], March 2, 1889; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking what report was made on his paper last Friday night.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 4, 1889; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Houghton, W. A., publisher
    New York, L. 1p. Offers G.B. Goode's American Fishes for sale.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, March 5, 1889; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Chaper, Maurice, 1834-1896
    Paris, A.L.S. 1p., end. In French. Requests material on international language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 5, 1889; 7x5-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden,N.J., A.L.S. 1p.and add. Enc.wanting. Concerning the packages.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 5, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Winship, Richard C.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about 1826 almanac.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 7, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his forthcoming paper on folk medicine.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 7, 1889; 4-1/2x9-1/2; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about journal of Asiatic Society of Bengal.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 10, 1889; 9-1/2x5-1/2; State Library of Massachusetts
    Boston, A.L.S.:C[aleb] B.Tillinghast. 1p. Enc. wanting. Cannot furnish any information relative to the enclosed title.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 11, 1889; 4x5; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    [Washington] A.L.S. 2p., end. Makes appointment to see MSS. of American linguistics at A.P.S.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 18, 1889; 10x8; Kocher, J. F.
    Guths Station P.O., Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about W.J. Hoffman's Pennsylvania Dutch Dictionary and Grammar.
  - Letter to [James Constantine Pilling;], March 20, 1889; 5-1/4x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L. 1p. Draft. Declines appointment. On verso of telegram from Pilling to Phillips, March 20, 1889.
  - Telegram to [Henry] Phillipps [sic], March 20, 1889; 5-1/4x8; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, Telegram S. 1p., end. Copy Makes appointment. On verso is draft of Phillips' reply. See [Henry] Phillips to [J.C. Pilling, March 20, 1889]
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, March 21, 1889; 8x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns paper withdrawn by E.D. Cope. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 22, 1889; 8x5-3/4; Hall, Charles H.
    Cambridgeport, Mass., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about W.M. Gabb's paper on topography and geography of San Domingo.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 22, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p. Has received extras of his paper. Is working on paper on folk medicine.
  - Telegram to Henry Phillips, March 23, 1889; 5-1/4x8; Pilling, James Constantine, 1846-1895
    Washington, D. 1p. and end., and add. Cancels appointment.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], March 23, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Princeton Theological Seminary
    Princeton, N.J., Printed L.S.: J.H. Dulles, Librarian. 1p. Inquires about size of library staff.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 24, 1889; 3x5; Horn, George H. (George Henry), 1840-1897
    [Phila.,]. A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns a meeting.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., March 25, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Keim, George de Benneville
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Sends receipt for Proceedings, No. 128.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March 25, 1889; 7-3/4x5; Pickell, George S.
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. and add. Concerns proofs.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., March 28, 1889; 10x7-3/4; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Proposes to present two papers to the A.P.S. Refers to W.B. Scott.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, March 30, 1889; 8x5; Princeton University
    Princeton, [N.J.], A.L.S.: Frederic Vinton, Librarian. 1p., end. About his set of the Transactions.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., March, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Biddle, Arthur, 1852-1897
    [?] Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. dated 2-IV-89. Sends copies of Appendix C.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, April 1, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends draft of form letter to accompany Phillips prize circular.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 1, [1889]; 10x7-3/4; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns MSS. and plates.
  - Letter to Patterson DuBois, April 3, 1889; 8-1/4x11; MacAlister, James, 1840-1913
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Do not wait but sign his name to the paper in question.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 4, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns circular to propose congress for establishment of an international language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 4, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns paper to be presented at next meeting. Refers to W.B. Scott.
  - Note of presentation, April 6, 1889; 7x4 1/2; Geikie, James, 1839-1915
    Edinburgh, A.N. in 3d person. 1p.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], April 7, 1889; 6-1/2x4-1/4; Planté, Gaston, 1834-1889
    Paris, A.L.S. 2p. Concerns receipt of Proceedings.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, April 8, 1889; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Hedeler, Georg, d. 1907
    Leipzig, L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Enc. wanting Refers to P.E. Richter's proposed list of "all considerable libraries." Sends form to be filled in and returned.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 8, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p Concerns MS. of his paper on "Folk-Medicine of the Pennsylvania-Germans." Goes to Minnesota to be honored by the Indians.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, April 9, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Refers to Michaux Legacy Committee, and to E.K. Price.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 9, 1889; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Rothrock, Joseph T., 1839-1922
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns the obituary of N.A. Randolph.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 10, 1889; 10x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns regulations for Henry M. Phillips Prize Essay Fund.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 11, 1889; 5x3; Du Bois, Patterson, 1847-1917
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Asking about his proofs. Concerning the committee.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 12, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Concerning the parcel he sent.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 16, 1889; 3x5-1/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. and add., end. Inquires about G.W. Anderson, T.C. Clarke, W.V. Keating, C. Wister, J.P Wetherill.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 17, 1889; 10x8; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends papers on folk-lore. Concerning his paper on Grammar and vocabulary.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 17, 1889; 10x7-1/2; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p.,end. Concerning the spelling in his paper. Concerning spelling reform.
  - Letter to secretary of A.P.S. [Henry Phillips], April 17, 1889; 8x5; Mott, Henry
    Montreal, A.L.S. 1p.,end. Asking for brochure on the Journal of A.Michaux.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 17, 1889; 7-3/4x4-3/4; Ridler, C. E.
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. Asks for information on pastoral written by Annis Boudinot Stockton to Washington, on occasion of Cornwallis' surrender.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 19, 1889; 3x5; Ridler, C. E.
    Boston, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Asks for information of Annis Boudinot Stockton.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 27, 1889; 3x5; Genth, F. A. (Frederick Augustus), 1855?-1910
    [Phila.], A.L.on postal card S. 1p.,end.,and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], April 29, 1889; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add.,end. Mutilated. Asking for announcement of his paper on the genus Hippotherium.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, April 29, 1889; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asking if any one has been elected in 1889.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., April 30, 1889; 8 1/2x5 1/4; Etting, Frank M. (Frank Marx)
    Concordville, Pa., A.L.S. 5p., end. Concerns Jefferson's draft of the Declaration of Independence, in A.P.S. collections.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 1, 1889; 10x7-1/2; Mooney, James, 1861-1921
    Wash.,D.C., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerning his paper on Funeral customs [of Ireland]. Concerning spelling reform.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 2, 1889; 10x7-1/2; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Thursday, A.L.S. 1p. Says he is going to see him about the memoir tomorrow morning.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Phila., May 2, 1889; 10x8; United States. Dept. of State
    Washington, [i.e., 1893]. L.S.: William F. Wharton, Assistant Secretary. 2p. Concerns circulars announcing Phillips essay prize.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 5, 1889; 3x5; Potts, William John, 1842-1895
    Camden,N.J., A.L.on postal card S. 1p.and add. Concerning publication by B.S.Schneck.
  - Letter to secretaries of A.P.S.[Henry Phillips], May 6, 1889; 6x8; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. Concerning the estimate for engraving.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., May 6, 1889; 10x8; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Suggests corrections in rules for Henry M. Phillips prize essay fund.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 8, 1889; 8x5; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc.wanting. Sends his remarks on the pronghorn.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., May 8, 1889; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hoffman, Walter James, 1846-1899
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on "Folk-Medicine of the Pennsylvania Germans." Refers to Col. [Garrick] Mallery. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol.26, pp.329-352.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 9, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:S[amuel] P.Langley,secretary. 1p.,end. Concerning domestic exchanges.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, May 13, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Says he has signed the circulars.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 14, 1889; 7x5; Worrall, Harvey
    Topeka, A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for report on amended orthography
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Phila., May 16, 1889; 3x5; Bonwill, William Gibson Arlington, 1833-1899
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Asks to read his paper, "Geometry and Mechanics Deny Evolution."
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 17, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Dalby, Henry
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p. Enc.wanting. Sends a copy of his Index of current events.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 18, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Wash.,D.C., Typed L.S.:S[amuel] P.Langley,secretary. 1p. Concerning exchanges.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips [sic], May 20, 1889; 7x4 1/2; Vaux, Richard, 1816-1895
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on sun and cross symbols. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, pp. 476-481.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., May 22, 1889; 9 1/2x6; J. B. Lippincott Company
    Phila., L. 1p. Cannot move books for A.P.S.
  - Letter to J[ohn] H. Hickcox, Washington, May 23, [1889]; 3x5; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., A.L. on postal card 1p., end. with Hickcox's reply. and add. Asks for recent numbers of his catalogue of U.S. government publications.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, May 25, 1889; 9x5 3/4; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns reproduction of Montezuma Tribute-roll.
  - Letter to McCalla & Co., Phila., May 28, 1889; 3x5; Cope, E. D. (Edward Drinker), 1840-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add., end. Concerns printing of a paper.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, May 29, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: S.P. Langley, Secretary. 1p. and add., end. Concerns packages for Numismatic and Antiquarian Society of Phila.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., May 31, 1889; 3x5; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, A.L.S.: Geo. H. Boekmer (?), Exchange Clerk, on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns return of packages for Connecticut Academy, etc.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 1, 1889; 6x9; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., A.L.S.: Geo. S. Pickell. 2p. and add., end. Concerns printing of A.P.S. papers. Refers to E.D. Cope, J.P. Lesley.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., June 1, 1889; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Has called meeting of committee on Centennial Celebration. Refers to C.A. Oliver.
  - Letter to [Frederick] Fraley, June 3, 1889; 8x5; Hays, I. Minis (Isaac Minis), 1847-1925
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Will prepare obituary for S.W. Gross.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 3, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns MS. and plates of his paper on "Mammalia of the Uinta Formation." Refers to Osborn, Marsh, Werner & Winter. For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol.16, part 3, pp.461-572. On verso of same sheet is draft of Phillips' reply. See Phillips to Scott, June 4, 1889.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 3, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Vaux, Richard, 1816-1895
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on sun and cross symbols. For paper, see: APS Proceedings, v.26, pp.476-481.
  - Letter to [William Berryman Scott], June 4, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Draft. Concerns Scott's paper on "Mammalia of the Uinta Formation." Refers to Osborn. Written on verso of letter from Scott to Phillips, June 3, 1889.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 4, 1889; 10-1/2x8; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., and end. Concerns plates for his paper on "Mammalia of the Uinta Formation." For printed paper, see: APS Transactions, vol.16, part 3, pp.461-572.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 5, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Davenport Academy of Natural Sciences
    Davenport, Iowa, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Jennie McCowan, Cha[rle]s E.Harrison. 1p.,end. Thanks for publication. Attached to same sheet as letter from Davenport academy of natural sciences to [Henry Phillips], Nov.18, 1889.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., June 5, 1889; 8x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting. Encloses I.M. Hays' agreement to write obituary of S.W. Gross. For letter of acceptance, see I.M. Hays to F. Fraley, June 3, 1889.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, June 6, 1889; 9 1/2x6; Denison University
    Granville, Ohio, A.L.S.: Mrs. J.E. Dixson [Librarian]. Concerns exchange of Publications.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 7, 1889; 8x5; Etting, Frank M. (Frank Marx)
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns his MS. on Jefferson draft of Declaration of Independence. See: APS Proceedings, p.355.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 8, 1889; 8x5; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns work to be done on Curators' collection by Mr. and Mrs. Nuhnesdorff.
  - Letter to W[illiam] B[erryman] Scott, Princeton, N.J., June 9, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Concerns printing of Scott's paper on "Mammals of the Uinta Formation."
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 10, 1889; 8-1/4x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns meeting of A.P.S. Centennial Committee. Refers to Charles A. Oliver.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 11, 1889; 10x8; Taylor, William B. (William Bower), 1821-1895
    Washington, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Thanks for copy of Subject-Register to Transactions and Proceedings. Requests copy of Fairman Rogers' obituary of Joseph Henry.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips [sic], Jr., June 12, 1889; 10x8; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Wm. F. Harrity, Postmaster. 1p. and end. Apology for error in handling mail.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 13, [1889]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Henderson, George J.
    London, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Thanks for report of Committee on Amended Orthografy. Refers to international language.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., June 15, 1889; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Gives date of meeting of committee for centennial celebration of A.P.S.
  - Letter to board of managers of the Pennsylvania hospital, June 19, 1889; 3x5; American Philosophical Society
    Phila., Printed L.on postal card filled in in ms. S.:Henry Phillips,secretary.1p.and add. Concerning publications.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], June 19, 1889; 8x5; Keyes, Charles Rollin, 1864-1942
    Burlington, Iowa, A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks for Copy of Proceedings with his paper on "Attachment of Platyceras to palaeocrinoids." For paper, see: APS Proceedings, PP. 231-243.
  - Letter to Messrs. J.D. & E.S. Dana, New Haven, Conn., June 21, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Kolb, J. B.
    Larangeiros, Brazil, A.L.S. 1p., end. Wants two copies of J.C. Branner's paper, "The Cretaceous and Tertiary Geology of the Sergipe-Alagoas Basin of Brazil" in A.P.S. Transactions, N.S., vol.16.
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., June 21, 1889; 3x5; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p. Concerns meeting of centennial celebration committee.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], June 24, 1889; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Columbia University. Library
    New York, A.L.S.: Wm. G. Baker, Ref. Librarian. 1p., end. Inquires after missing volume of A.P.S. Transactions.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, June 24, 1889; 7-3/4x10; Osborn, Henry Fairfield, 1857-1935
    Princeton, N.J., A.L.S. 2p., end., and add., end. Concerns his and W.B. Scott's paper on "Mammalia of the Uinta Formation."
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], June 25, 1889; 8x5; Keyes, Charles Rollin, 1864-1942
    Burlington, Iowa, A.L.S. 1p., end. Sends postage for copy of his paper on "Attachment of Platyceras to Palaeocrinoids."
  - Letter to H[enry] Phillips, Jr., June 25, 1889; 9x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns his obituary of Franklin Peale. Refers to C.W. Peale.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, June 27, 1889; 8-3/4x5-1/2; Morris, J. Cheston (James Cheston), 1831-1923
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. About reproduction of Montezuma tributeroll.
  - Letter to Henry M. Phillips [sic, July 1, 1889; 8x5; Vaux, Richard, 1816-1895
    Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. About plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Refers to W.S.W. Ruschenberger.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], July 5, 1889; 11x8; Darling, Charles W. (Charles William), 1830-1905
    Utica, N.Y., Printed L. 1p., end. Concerns his proposed checklist of versions of the Bible.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 6, 1889; 8x5-1/2; Wilson, William P. (William Powell), 1844-1927
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns printing of his paper.
  - Letter to the Secretaries of the A.P.S., July 12, 1889; 8X5; Messchert, Matthew Huizinga, 1831-1904
    Douglassville, pa., A.L.S. 1p. About his photograph for the A.P.S. Album.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 15, 1889; 7x4-1/2; Emerson, Ellen Russell, 1837-1907
    Plymouth, Mass., A.L.S. 2p. Requests reproductions of Mexican masks in A.P.S. collection.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, July 17, 1889; 8x4-3/4; Price, John Sergeant, 1831-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerns plans for A.P.S. centennial celebration. Refers to R. Vaux. Humorous.
  - Letter to Henry Philips [sic], Jr., July 19, 1889; 9x5-3/4; Sheppard, Edwin L., d. 1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Sends in bill for drawings for E.D.Cope's paper on North American Hippotherium. Refers to J.S. Price.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, July 20, 1889; 6-3/4x5-1/2; Pennsylvania engraving co. Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns plantes for E.D. Cope's paper on North American Hippotherium.
  - Letter to the Secretary of the A.P.S., July 25, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Adam, Lucien, 1833-1918
    Rennes, France, A.L.S. 1p., end. Enc. Sends receipt for Proceedings, No.129. Thanks for membership application.
  - Letter to H[enry] F[airfield] Osborn, Garrisons, N.Y., [July?] 28, 1889; 7-3/4x5-1/2; Phillips, Henry, 1838-1895
    Phila., L.S. 1p. Concerns an "oral presentation."
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., July 29, 1889; 8x5; Boyè, Martin H. (Martin Hans), b. 1812
    Coopersburg, Pa., A.L.S. 1p., end. Wants copies of Report on Amended Orthografy.
  - Letter to Henry Philipps [sic], Jr., July 30, 1889; 5-1/2x8; Beale, Charles Currier, 1864-1909
    Boston, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Requests copies of A.P.S. reports on Volapük.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, July 31, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Dalby, Henry
    Montreal, A.L.S. 2p., end. Concerns A.P.S. subscription to his Index of current events.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], July 31, 1889; 7-1/4x4-1/2, 8-3/4x6; Victoria Insititute (Great Britain)
    London, A.L.S.: J. Petrie. 2p., and end. Enc. Returns printed List of deficiencies in A.P.S. library, with corrections and comments.
  - Letter to [Henry] Phillips, Aug. 5, 1889; 8-1/2x5; Oliver, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), b. 1853
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. Concerning the college presidents chosen by the committee. Refers to Max Müller.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Aug. 13, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Rothery, Davis & Co. Philadelphia
    Phila., L. 1p. Offers collection of antique pottery for sale.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Phila., Aug. 14, 1889; 11x8-1/2; Funk & Wagnalls
    New York, Typed L. 1p., end. Concerns file of its publication, the Voice.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Aug. 21, 1889; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Washburn College
    Topeka, Kan., A.L.S.: L.D. Whitten, Librarian. 1p., end. Encs. wanting. Sends receipts for Proceedings, Nos. 125, 129. Has not received No. 126.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Jr., Aug. 22, 1889; 10x8; United States. Post Office, Philadelphia
    Phila., Typed L.S.: Henry Drake, Assistant Postmaster. 1p. Enc. wanting. Concerns error in handling mail.
  - Letter to [Henry Phillips], Aug. 28, 1889; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Foote, Albert E., 1846-1895
    Phila., L. 1p., end. Concerns purchase of set of Transactions and Proceedings.